<bcrdCorpus xmlns="http://www.bcrdb.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="bcrd">
	<head>
		<doc id="2-05-00015-ENG02_Brunn.xml"/>
		<title>Kāyatraya-stotra</title>
		<author>Nāgārjuna</author>
		<unifiedCatalogID>2-05-00015</unifiedCatalogID>
		<creation date="Sun Aug  6 17:07:00 2017"/>
		<processed date="Sun Aug  6 17:07:00 2017" ver="AbbyyFineReader v.11" auth="Hackett"/>
		<sourceDesc>
			<bibl>
				<title>Straight From The Heart: Buddhist Pith Instructions</title>
				<author>Brunnholzl, Karl</author>
				<pubPlace>Ithaca</pubPlace>
				<publisher>Snow Lion Publications</publisher>
				<date>2007</date>
				<biblScope unit="pageRange">18-19</biblScope>
				<note type="Text Colophon">Initially translated by Karl Brunnholzl from Sanskrit; edited and reformatted by Paul Hackett.</note>
			</bibl>
		</sourceDesc>
	</head>
	<text>
		<text_id t_id="2-05-00015-ENG02"/>
		<sentence s_id="2-05-00015-ENG02-SID000001" type="Text Title">
			<phrase phr_id="2-05-00015-ENG02-000001">In Praise of the Three Kāyas</phrase>
		</sentence>
		<volume vol_id="1"/>
		<sentence s_id="2-05-00015-ENG02-SID000002" type="Sentence">
			<phrase phr_id="2-05-00015-ENG02-000002"><page p_id="18"/>Homage to the Buddha!</phrase>
		</sentence>
		<sentence s_id="2-05-00015-ENG02-SID000003" type="Verse" s_name="1">
			<phrase phr_id="2-05-00015-ENG02-000003">What is neither one nor many, the foundation of great and excellent benefit for oneself and others,</phrase>
			<phrase phr_id="2-05-00015-ENG02-000004">Neither an entity nor the lack of an entity, of equal taste like space, of a nature difficult to perceive,</phrase>
			<phrase phr_id="2-05-00015-ENG02-000005">Untainted, changeless, peaceful, unequalled, all-pervading, and free from reference points—</phrase>
			<phrase phr_id="2-05-00015-ENG02-000006"><page p_id="19"/>To the incomparable dharmakāya of the Victors, which is to be personally experienced, I pay homage. [1]</phrase>
		</sentence>
		<sentence s_id="2-05-00015-ENG02-SID000004" type="Verse" s_name="2">
			<phrase phr_id="2-05-00015-ENG02-000007">What is beyond the world, inconceivable, the very embodiment of the fruition of hundreds of excellent accomplishments, and magnificent,</phrase>
			<phrase phr_id="2-05-00015-ENG02-000008">Displays great variety in the middle of a retinue due to being the cause for the pleasure of the wise,</phrase>
			<phrase phr_id="2-05-00015-ENG02-000009">And is the Buddhas' unceasing, eloquent melody of the genuine dharma, resounding in all the worlds—</phrase>
			<phrase phr_id="2-05-00015-ENG02-000010">To the sambhogakāya, residing in the kingdom of the great dharma, I pay homage. [2]</phrase>
		</sentence>
		<sentence s_id="2-05-00015-ENG02-SID000005" type="Verse" s_name="3">
			<phrase phr_id="2-05-00015-ENG02-000011">As the cause for maturing sentient beings, sometimes, it shines like the blaze of a fire,</phrase>
			<phrase phr_id="2-05-00015-ENG02-000012">At others, it appears as buddhahood, the wheel of dharma, or as gaining peace,</phrase>
			<phrase phr_id="2-05-00015-ENG02-000013">Operating in various ways, it dispells the fear of threefold existence through all kinds of means—</phrase>
			<phrase phr_id="2-05-00015-ENG02-000014">To the nirmānakāya of the Sages, the great welfare that pervades the ten directions, I pay homage. [3]</phrase>
		</sentence>
		<sentence s_id="2-05-00015-ENG02-SID000006" type="Verse" s_name="4">
			<phrase phr_id="2-05-00015-ENG02-000015">Liberated from the conduct of the three realms, equal to the sky, the nature of all entities,</phrase>
			<phrase phr_id="2-05-00015-ENG02-000016">Pure, peaceful, free, embodying utter serenity, to be realized by yogins,</phrase>
			<phrase phr_id="2-05-00015-ENG02-000017">Difficult to realize, hard to examine, the benefit of oneself and others, all-encompassing, and causeless–</phrase>
			<phrase phr_id="2-05-00015-ENG02-000018">To the kāya of the Victors in its single form, which is blissful, unequalled, and nonconceptual, I pay homage. [4]</phrase>
		</sentence>
	</text>
</bcrdCorpus>