<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<root>
    <metadata>
        <title>Swamp Skiin Throwdown</title>
    </metadata>
    <section>
        <description>The short opens with a shot of a leaf falling on the swamp, making it shine. A
            catgator surfaces from underneath the leaf, and the camera pans up to show Due and Tho
            watching Sokka making something.</description>
    </section>
    <section>
        <speech speaker="Tho">Sokka, shouldn't you be doing something fun, <charAction>A closer shot
                of Due and Tho.</charAction> or more manly?</speech>
    </section>
    <section>
        <speech speaker="Sokka"><charAction>Puts a finger of Tho's mouth to quiet him.</charAction>
            Pay attention, simpleton. This ... <charAction>Camera pans to show a hollowed out
                pumpkin with two leaves on top.</charAction> is a water filtration device.
                <charAction>Runs over to it.</charAction> See, your filthy swamp water sits in this
            hollowed-out pumpkin. Then the sunlight makes the water evaporate, leaving behind the
            swampy impurities.</speech>
    </section>
    <section>
        <speech speaker="Tho">You mean the flavor?</speech>
    </section>
    <section>
        <speech speaker="Sokka"><charAction>Sarcastically.</charAction> Yes, genius. It leaves
            behind the filthy swamp flavor. Then the clean water vapor collects on the leaf, and
            drips into this nice, sanitized cup. <charAction>Holds up the cup and takes a refreshing
                drink.</charAction> Ah! I do love clean water.</speech>
    </section>
    <section>
        <speech speaker="Aang"><charAction>From off-camera.</charAction> What'd you say, brain boy?
                <charAction>The camera pans to Aang swamp skiing.</charAction> You love water?
            Yee-haw!</speech>
    </section>
    <section>
        <description>Aang creates a large wave, soaking Sokka and destroying his water filtration
            device.</description>
    </section>
    <section>
        <speech speaker="Tho">What you gonna do now?</speech>
    </section>
    <section>
        <speech speaker="Sokka"><charAction>Very angrily.</charAction> What do you think I'm going
            to do, leaf head?! I'm going to rebuild my water filtration device!</speech>
    </section>
    <section>
        <speech speaker="Tho">Boy, that there's a swamp skiin' throwdown. You can't be playing with
            pumpkin juice when there's a throwdown. It just ain't manly.</speech>
    </section>
    <section>
        <speech speaker="Sokka">But ...</speech>
    </section>
    <section>
        <speech speaker="Tho"><charAction>His head suddenly becomes big and red.</charAction>
            Throwdown! <charAction>Sokka does a flip and falls on his head.</charAction> Hey Due,
            get the boat. <charAction>Due walks on-camera carrying a boat.</charAction> We're going
            swamp skiin'.</speech>
    </section>
    <section>
        <description>At the river shore, Tho and Due put a flotation device on Sokka.</description>
    </section>
    <section>
        <speech speaker="Due">Safety first.</speech>
    </section>
    <section>
        <description>Due positions Sokka over the skis. Sokka squirms when he sees a worm, beetle,
            snail, and fish in one of the skis. Sokka evades every attempt Due makes to place him in
            the skis.</description>
    </section>
    <section>
        <speech speaker="Tho">Get your dang feet in the skis, or I'll strap you to Old Slim
            instead.</speech>
    </section>
    <section>
        <description>Pan to Slim, the catgator, who bites the pumpkin from Sokka's water filtration
            device. Some of the pumpkin juice lands on Sokka. Due finally manages to get Sokka into
            the skis, and Sokka's face turns blue. Out on the river, Sokka holds a rope tied to Tho
            and Due's boat.</description>
    </section>
    <section>
        <speech speaker="Due">You ready?</speech>
    </section>
    <section>
        <speech speaker="Sokka"><charAction>Flatly.</charAction> No.</speech>
    </section>
    <section>
        <speech speaker="Tho">Hit it. Throwdown.</speech>
    </section>
    <section>
        <description>Tho grabs the rudder and Due swings his arms with engine sounds. Sokka
            immediately falls out of his skis and skids along the water until he lets go of the
            rope. A closer shot of Sokka surfacing while Aang quickly skis by in the background
            laughing.</description>
    </section>
    <section>
        <speech speaker="Tho">This time keep your knees bent and your tuckus tucked.</speech>
    </section>
    <section>
        <speech speaker="Due">Speaking of your tuckus, looks like Old Slim's got your
            pants.</speech>
    </section>
    <section>
        <description>Slim holds Sokka's trunks in his mouth stretching it like a muzzle.
            Embarrassed, Sokka lowers most of his head back in the water. Sokka tries to swamp ski
            again, but quickly gets pulled underwater. When he resurfaces, he finds he is now riding
            on Slim, who manages to bite off Sokka's trunks again as he jumps onto a tree branch.
            Aang, riding on one ski, swings by, and a camera shutter clicks when he passes Sokka.
            Sokka's face becomes red. Cut to Sokka attempting another round of swamp skiing. He
            loses one ski and crashes into tree vines. Aang splashes Sokka, and Aang does a large
            trick to jump on the head of Appa, who is also skiing. Cut to later, when Sokka is
            resurfacing from another round of swamp skiing.</description>
    </section>
    <section>
        <speech speaker="Sokka">Guys, can I get out of the water now?</speech>
    </section>
    <section>
        <speech speaker="Tho">You tell me. <charAction>To Due.</charAction> Hit it.</speech>
    </section>
    <section>
        <description>This time, Sokka manages to ski.</description>
    </section>
    <section>
        <speech speaker="Sokka">I-I ... I did it! I'm swamp skiing! <charAction>His eyes make heart
                symbols.</charAction> I love swamp skiing ...! <charAction>The camera pans back to
                the whole world and back to Sokka. Aang swings by, smiling.</charAction> In your
            face, air boy. Who's swamp skiing now?</speech>
    </section>
    <section>
        <speech speaker="Aang">Not you.</speech>
    </section>
    <section>
        <description>Aang uses waterbending to freeze a ramp for Sokka to jump off, sending the
            whole boat sailing through the air and crashing into the swamp.</description>
    </section>
    <section>
        <speech speaker="Sokka"><charAction>Falling down the trunk of the tree.</charAction> I hate
            swamp skiing.</speech>
    </section>
    <section>
        <description>Slim bites off Sokka's trunks. Due and Tho celebrate the day of swamp
            skiing.</description>
    </section>
    <section>
        <speech speaker="Tho">Whoo, now that there's a throwdown!</speech>
    </section>
    <section>
        <description>Fade to credits.</description>
    </section>
</root>