<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../drSuesSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?><book>
<metadata genre="rhyme" type="moral" date="1958"/>
<title>The Cat in the Hat Comes Back</title>
<body>
<stanza>
<l> This was no time for play.</l>
<l> This was no time for fun.</l>
<l> This was no time for games.</l>
<l> There was work to be done.</l>
<l> All the deep, deep, deep snow</l>
<l> All that snow had to go.</l>
<l> When our mother went down to the town for the day, </l>
<l> She said, "Somebody has to clean all this away. Somebody, Somebody has to, you see." </l>
<l> Then she picked out two somebodies: Sally and me.</l>
</stanza>
<stanza>
<l> Well…there we were.</l>
<l> We were working like that</l>
<l> And then who should come up</l>
<l> But the CAT IN THE HAT! </l>
<l> “Oh-oh!” Sally said. “Don’t you talk to that cat.</l>
<l> That cat is a bad one,</l>
<l> That Cat in the Hat.</l>
<l> He plays lots of bad tricks.</l>
<l> Don’t you let him come near.</l>
<l> You know what he did the last time he was here.”</l>
<l> “Play tricks?” laughed the cat. “Oh, my my! No, no, no!</l>
<l> I just want to go in</l>
<l> To get out of the snow.</l>
<l> Keep your mind on your work.</l>
<l> You just stay there, you two.</l>
<l> I will go in the house and find something to do.”</l>
<l> Then the cat went right in!</l>
<l> He was up to no good!</l>
<l> So I ran in after as fast as I could!</l>
<l> Do you know where I found him?</l>
</stanza>
<stanza>
<l> You know where he was?</l>
<l> He was eating a cake in the tub!</l>
<l> Yes he was! The hot water was on and the cold water, too.</l>
<l> And I said to the cat, “What a bad thing to do!” </l>
<l> “But I like to eat cake in a tub,” laughed the cat.</l>
<l> “You should try it sometime,” laughed the cat as he sat.</l>
<l> And then I got mad.</l>
<l> This was no time for fun.</l>
<l> I said, “Cat! You get out! There is work to be done. </l>
<l> I have no time for tricks. I must go back and dig.</l>
<l> I can’t have you in here eating cake like a pig!</l>
<l> You get out of this house! We don’t want you about!”</l>
<l> Then I shut off the water and let it run out.</l>
<l> The water ran out and then I saw THE RING!</l>
<l> A ring in the tub! And, oh boy! What a thing!</l>
<l> A big long pink cat ring! It looked like pink ink!</l>
<l> And I said, “Will this ever come off? I don’t think!”</l>
</stanza>
<stanza>
<l> “Have no fear of that ring” laughed the cat in the hat.</l>
<l> Why, I can take cat rings off tubs just like that!”</l>
<l> Do you know how he did it? WITH MOTHER’S WHITE DRESS!</l>
<l> Now the tub was all clean, but her dress was a mess!</l>
<l> Then Sally looked in. Sally saw the dress, too!</l>
<l> And Sally and I did not know what to do.</l>
<l> We should work in the snow but that dress! </l>
<l> What a spot! “It may never come off!” Sally said. “It may not!”</l>
<l> “Ho Ho, I can make the spot go.</l>
<l> The way I take spots off a dress is just so!</l>
<l> See here!” laughed the cat. “It is not hard at all.</l>
<l> The thing that takes spots off a dress is a wall.”</l>
<l> Then we saw the cat wipe the spot off the dress.</l>
<l> Now the dress was all clean but the wall! What a mess! </l>
<l> “Oh, wall spots!” he laughed. “Let me tell you some news.</l>
<l> To take spots off a wall, all I need is two shoes!”</l>
<l> Whose shoes did he use? I looked and saw whose!</l>
<l> And I said to the cat, “This is very bad news.</l>
<l> Now the spot is all over dad’s 10 dollar shoes!”</l>
</stanza>
<stanza>
<l> “But your dad will not know about that,” said the cat.</l>
<l> “He will never find out,” laughed the cat in the hat.</l>
<l> “His $10 shoes will have no spots at all.</l>
<l> I will rub them right off on this rug in the hall.”</l>
<l> “But now we have rug spots!” I yelled.</l>
<l> “What a day! Rug spots! What next? Can you take them away?”</l>
<l> “Don’t ask me,” he laughed. “Why, you know that I can!”</l>
<l> Then he picked up the rug and away the cat ran.</l>
<l> “I can clean up these rug spots before you count three!</l>
<l> No spots are too hard for a Hat Cat like me!”</l>
<l> He ran into Dad’s bedroom and then the cat said, </l>
<l> “It is good that your dad has the right kind of bed.”</l>
<l> Then he shook the rug! CRACK! Now the bed had the spot! </l>
<l> And all I could say was,“Now what, Cat? Now what?”</l>
<l> But the cat stood still. He just looked at the bed. </l>
<l> “This is not the right kind of bed,” the cat said.</l>
<l> “To take spots off THIS bed will be hard,” said the cat.</l>
<l> I can’t do it alone,” said the cat in the hat. </l>
<l> “It is good I have someone to help me” he said.</l>
<l> “Right here in my hat on the top of my head!</l>
<l> It is good that I have him here with me today.</l>
<l> He helps me a lot, this is Little Cat A. “</l>
<l> And then Little Cat A took the hat off his head.</l>
<l> “It is good I have someone to help me,” he said.</l>
<l> “This is Little Cat B and I keep him about,</l>
<l> and when I need help then I let him out.”</l>
<l> Then B said, “I think we need Little Cat C. </l>
<l> That spot is too much for the A cat and me.</l>
<l> But now, have no fear! We will clean it away! </l>
<l> The three of us! Little Cats B, C, and A!”</l>
<l> “Come on! Take it away!” yelled little cat A. </l>
<l> I will hit that old spot with this broom! Do you see?</l>
<l> It comes off the old bed! It goes on the T.V.”</l>
<l> And then Little Cat B cleaned up the T.V.</l>
<l> He cleaned it with milk, put the spot in a pan!</l>
<l> And then C blew it out of the house with a fan!</l>
<l> “But look where it went!” I said. “Look where it blew!</l>
<l> You blew the mess out of the house. That is true.</l>
<l> But now you made Snow Spots! You can’t let THEM stay!” </l>
<l> “Let us think about that now,” said C, B, and A. </l>
<l> “With some help, we can do it!” said little cat C.</l>
<l> Then POP! On his head we saw Little Cat D!</l>
<l> Then, POP! POP! POP! Little Cats E, F, and G! </l>
<l> “We will clean up that snow if it takes us all day!</l>
<l> If it takes us all night, we will clean it away!” said little cats G, F,E,D,C,B,A.</l>
<l> They ran out of the house then and we ran out, too. </l>
<l> And the big cat laughed, “Ha ha, now you will see something new. </l>
<l> My cats are all clever. My cats are good shots</l>
<l> My cats have good guns, they will kill all those spots.”</l>
<l> But this did not look very clever to me. </l>
<l> Kill snow spots with pop guns? That just couldn’t be.</l>
<l> “All this does is make more spots,” we yelled at the cat.</l>
<l> “Your cats are no good. Put them back in your hat. </l>
<l> Take your Little Cats G, F, E, D, C, B, A.</l>
<l> Put them back in your hat and take them away!“</l>
<l> “Oh, no!” said the cat. “All they need is more help.</l>
<l> Help is all that they need. </l>
<l> So keep still and don’t yelp. </l>
<l> Then Little G took the hat off his head. </l>
<l> “I have Little Cat H here to help us” he said. </l>
<l> “Little Cats H, I, J, K, L, M. But our work is so hard</l>
<l> We must have more than them. We need Little Cat N. </l>
<l> We need O. We need P. We need Little Cats Q, R, S, T, U and V. </l>
<l> “Come on! Get rid of those spots!” said the cats. “Get rid of the mess!” </l>
<l> And they jumped at the snow with long rakes and red bats.</l>
<l> They put it in pails and they made high pink hills! </l>
<l> Pink snow men! Pink snow balls! And little pink pills!</l>
<l> Oh, the things that they did and they did them so hard.</l>
<l> It was all one big spot now all over the yard!</l>
<l> But the Big Cat stood there and he said, “This is good.</l>
<l> This is what they should do and I knew that they would. </l>
<l> With a little more help all the work will be done. </l>
<l> They need one more cat and I know just the one.</l>
<l> Look close in my hand. I have Little Cat V.</l>
<l> On his head are Cats W, X, Y and Z. </l>
<l> Z is too small to see so don’t try. You cannot. </l>
<l> But Z is the cat who will clean up that spot! </l>
<l> Now here is the Z you can’t see,” said the cat.</l>
<l> And I bet you can’t guess what he has in his hat.</l>
<l> He has something called VOOM.</l>
<l> VOOM is so hard to get</l>
<l> You never saw anything like it, I bet.</l>
<l> Why VOOM cleans up anything, clean as can be.</l>
<l> The he yelled, “Take your hat off now, little cat Z.</l>
<l> Take the VOOM off our head.</l>
<l> Make it clean up the snow,</l>
<l> Hurry you little cat one, two, three go.”</l>
<l> Then the Voom… it went VOOM! </l>
<l> And, oh boy! What a VOOM!</l>
</stanza>
<stanza>
<l> Now don’t ask me what VOOM is. I never will know.</l>
<l> But, boy! Let me tell you it DOES clean up snow! </l>
<l> “Ha ha, So you see!” laughed the cat. “Now your snow is all white! </l>
<l> Now your work is all done! Now your house is all right! </l>
<l> And you know where my little cats are?” said the cat. </l>
<l> “That VOOM blew my little cats back in my hat.</l>
<l> And so, if you ever have spots, now and then, </l>
<l> I will be very happy to come here again… With Little Cats A, B, C, D, E, </l>
<l> F, G, H, I, J, K, L, M, N, and O, P, Q, R, S, T, </l>
<l> and cat U and cat V and little Cats W, X, Y and Z.”</l>
</stanza>
</body>
</book>