<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../drSuesSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?><book>
<metadata genre="rhyme" type="literacy" date="1955"/>
<title>On Beyond Zebra</title>
<body>
<stanza>
<l>
Said
<char name="Conrad Cornelius o'Donald o'Dell">Conrad Cornelius o'Donald o'Dell</char>
,
</l>
<l>My very young friend who is learning to spell:</l>
<l>"The A is for Ape. And B is for Bear.</l>
<l>The C is for Camel. The H is for Hare</l>
<l>The M is for Mouse. And the R is for Rat."</l>
<l>"I know all the twenty-six letters like that. . .</l>
<l>. . . Through to Z is for Zebra. I know them all well."</l>
<l>
Said
<char name="Conrad Cornelius o'Donald o'Dell">Conrad Cornelius o'Donald o'Dell</char>
.
</l>
<l>"So now I know everything anyone knows.</l>
<l>From beginning to end. From the start to the close.</l>
<l>Because Z is as far as the alphabet goes."</l>
</stanza>
<stanza>
<l>Then he almost fell flat on his face on the floor</l>
<l>When I picked up the chalk and drew one letter more!</l>
<l>A letter he never had dreamed of before!</l>
<l>And I said, "You can stop, if you want, with the Z.</l>
<l>Because most people stop with the Z.</l>
<l>But not me!!!</l>
<l>In the places I go, there are things that I see</l>
<l>That I never could spell if I stopped with the Z.</l>
<l>I'm telling you this 'cause you're one of my friends.</l>
<l>My alphabet starts where your alphabet ends!"</l>
</stanza>
<stanza>
<l>
"My alphabet starts with this letter called
<mUp>YUZZ</mUp>
.
</l>
<l>
It's the letter I use to spell
<mUp>YUZZ-a-ma-TUZZ</mUp>
.
</l>
<l>You'll be sort of surprised what there is to be found</l>
<l>Once you go beyond Z and start poking around!</l>
<l>So, on beyond Zebra!</l>
<l>Explore!</l>
<l>Like Columbus!</l>
<l>Discover new letters!</l>
<l>
Like
<mUp>WUM</mUp>
is for
<char name="Wumbus">Wumbus</char>
,
</l>
<l>My high-spouting whale who lives high on a hill</l>
<l>And who never comes down 'till it's time to refill.</l>
<l>So, on beyond Z! It's high time you were shown</l>
<l>That you really don't know all there is to be known."</l>
</stanza>
<stanza>
<l>
"Then just step a step further past
<mUp>Wum</mUp>
is for
<char name="Wumbus">Wumbus</char>
</l>
<l>
And there you'll find
<mUp>UM</mUp>
. And the
<mUp>Um</mUp>
is for
<mUp>Umbus</mUp>
</l>
<l>A sort of Cow, with one head and one tail,</l>
<l>But to milk this great cow you need more than one pail!</l>
<l>She has ninety-eight teats that give milk quite nicely.</l>
<l>Perhaps ninety-nine. I forget just precisely.</l>
<l>And, boy! She is something most people don't see.</l>
<l>Because most people stop at the Z</l>
<l>But not me!"</l>
</stanza>
<stanza>
<l>"If you stay home with Zebra,</l>
<l>You're stuck in a rut.</l>
<l>But on beyond Zebra,</l>
<l>You're anything but!</l>
<l>When you go beyond Zebra,</l>
<l>Who knows. . .?</l>
<l>There's no telling</l>
<l>What wonderful things</l>
<l>You might find yourself spelling!"</l>
</stanza>
<stanza>
<l>
"Like
<mUp>QUAN</mUp>
is for
<char name="Quandary">Quandary</char>
, who lives on a shelf
</l>
<l>In a hole in the ocean alone by himself</l>
<l>And he worries, each day, from the dawn's early light</l>
<l>And he worries, just worries, far into the night.</l>
<l>He just stands there and worries. He simply can't stop. . .</l>
<l>Is his top-side his bottom? Or bottom-side his top?"</l>
<l>So you see!</l>
<l>There's no end</l>
<l>To the things you might know,</l>
<l>Depending how far beyond Zebra you go!</l>
</stanza>
<stanza>
<l>The places I took him!</l>
<l>I tried hard to tell</l>
<l>
Young
<char name="Conrad Cornelius o'Donald o'Dell">Conrad Cornelius o'Donald o'Dell</char>
</l>
<l>A few brand-new wonderful words he might spell.</l>
<l>I led him around and I tried hard to show</l>
<l>There are things beyond Z that most people don't know.</l>
<l>I took him past Zebra. As far as I could.</l>
<l>And I think, perhaps, maybe I did him some good. . .</l>
</stanza>
<stanza>
<l>Because, finally, he said:</l>
<l>"This is really great stuff!</l>
<l>And I guess the old alphabet</l>
<l>ISN"T enough!"</l>
<l>NOW the letters he uses are something to see!</l>
<l>Most people stop at the Z. . .</l>
<l>But not HE!</l>
</stanza>
</body>
</book>